# 大爷
Da Ye
# 煎粉条还真是第一次
This is my first time to see fried vermicelli
# 我也头一次看见
Me too
# 牛肉粉条披萨
Beef vermicelli 'pizza'
# 河南嘞
From Henan
# 你说说 怎么样
How do you like it?
# 牛肉煎粉条
Beef with fried vermicelli
# 非常接地气
This is a down-to-earth dish
# 家庭主妇都会做
Everyone can cook it easily
# 也是河南商丘来的
It's also from Shangqiu, Henan
# 开始做呗
Let's start
# 这个粉条是红薯粉
This vermicelli is made from sweet potato starch
# 水温在40度的水温
The water temperature is about 40 degrees Celsius
# 浸泡1到2个小时
Soak it for 1 to 2 hours
# 千万不要用特别开的水
Do not use boiling water, or very hot water
# 牛肉煎粉条肯定得有牛肉
In this dish, we must have beef
# 咱这个是煮熟的牛肉
This is boiled beef
# 我们家里边有时候懒得做
If you don't want to cook it at home
# 到外边买点熟牛肉一切就行了
You can simply buy some cooked beef in shops
# 还有鸡蛋 4个鸡蛋
And eggs. 4 eggs
# 首先咱们先把牛肉放里面
Let's put the beef in the bowl
# 大爷这菜好
Da Ye, this will be a nice dish
# 还有那个青红椒米
And minced green and red chili peppers
# 放一部分
Add a part of it
# 咱们把蒜末跟姜末
Let's add some minced garlic and ginger
# 少许
Just a little
# 这时候咱们再加一点葱花
Let's add some minced green onion now
# 这个菜有点意思啊
This is an interesting dish
# 大概咱们放得五克盐
Let's add 5 grams of salt
# 稍微点一点点胡椒粉
A little white pepper powder
# 放一克糖
One gram of sugar
# 就让它提提鲜
To elevate the umami taste
# 但是还有一个
One more thing is that...
# 就是我们老家都爱吃十三香
The 'thirteen spices' is very popular in my hometown
# 还得放一点点十三香
Add some 'thirteen spices' as well
# 十三香嘞
The thirteen spices...
# 十三香不能放那么重
You don't need to add too much
# 轻轻的有一点
Just a little bit
# 那种感觉味道就行了
To give a slight touch of the taste
# 这时候咱们一定给它完全搅拌开了
Now we must mix it up
# 搅拌均匀
Mix until uniform
# 中原大地
In the middle plains
# 古代出了谁你知道吗
Do you know who came from there in the history?
# 出了包公
Bao gong (Justice Bao)
# 烹饪界又出现了
While in the culinary world
# 李党这样的优秀人才
There are great talents like Li Dang (who is also from that area)
# 这我师叔夸的
That's overpraising me, Er Bai
# 我这都 这鸡蛋都打不成了
I cannot even crack open the egg properly
# 我再表扬你两句
If I praise you more
# 你跟我比跟你师父还亲呢
You will like me more than your master
# 谁都爱听好话
Everyone likes being flattered
# 少倒一点点油 先煎粉条
Add a little oil to fry the vermicelli first
# 先把这个粉条给它放锅里
Add the vermicelli into the wok
# 给它打乱  打乱了之后
Stir it, then...
# 就是厚度让它一定要匀称
Make sure that the thickness is uniform everywhere
# 这个方法很新鲜
This method is rarely seen
# 要说真是地方特色
This is very special to my hometown
# 还是那句话美食在民间
Still, 'Delicious food is always folk food'
# 一定要小一点点火
Always use low heat
# 上面那一部分 一定都让它软了
Make sure that the top part becomes soft
# 软了一化 它能粘在一块
When it becomes soft and melts, it'll stick together
# 粘在一块儿的时候
When it sticks together
# 咱们可以来个大翻勺了
We can toss the wok
# 嘿 你看见没有
Hey. See that?
# 就这么恶劣的条件
We don't have proper woks or equipments today (compared with professional kitchens)
# 一翻就过来
He can flip it in one time
# 这时候你看
At this time
# 上下它马上都快粘在一块
The upper and the lower surface will stick together
# 有点意思了大爷
It's beginning to be interesting, Da Ye
# 有意思
Indeed
# 金黄
Golden yellow
# 这时候金黄了
It's golden yellow now
# 可以开大点火了
We can use higher heat
# 大爷 这煎粉条还真是第一次
This is my first time to see fried vermicelli
# 我也头一次看见
Me too
# 这个吃法还是挺新鲜的
This is a rarely seen method
# 为什么大爷
Why, Da Ye
# 不懂的我们绝不会乱加评价
It's because we would not comment on anything if we don't understand it
# 现在重复一下
Let me emphasize it again
# 泡这粉条一定要
You must soak the vermicelli...
# 40度水泡俩小时
for 2 hours at 40 degrees Celsius
# 然后得煎
Then fry it
# 油不能大
Do not add too much oil
# 然后再煎成慢慢的煎成淡黄色的
Then fry it slowly until it becomes pale yellow
# 你看到没有 大爷
See that, Da Ye?
# 不会做 我会学呀
I can learn to cook it even if I don't know how to cook it
# 这个粉条你看里面呢有水分
The vermicelli... you see, there's moisture inside
# 稍微要挤一下
You need to squeeze it
# 表面焦里面是嫩的那种感觉
to give a crispy texture on the surface, while it's still tender inside
# 煎的差不多了 小点火
That's almost done for frying. Turn down the heat
# 这时候咱们可以放那个
Now let's add
# 打好的鸡蛋 牛肉
the prepared eggs and beef
# 一定要完全给它盖上
We must cover it completely
# 盖上以后等一会咱们翻一下之后
After flipping it
# 那一面再加个背面
We can cover the lower side as well
# 双面都有 两面披萨
(The egg and beef) will be on both sides. Double-sided pizza
# 牛肉粉条披萨
Beef vermicelli pizza
# 河南嘞
From Henan
# 这时候淋一点点油
Now add some oil
# 你看看
Look
# 这时候得来个翻勺了
Now toss the wok
# 这个不好翻啊
This is a hard one
# 漂亮
Nice
# 这时候呢咱们跟刚才一样
Similar to what we did before
# 两面披萨
Double-sided pizza
# 这样翻过来
In this way
# 两面全是牛肉
We will have beef on both sides
# 我翻一下
Let me flip it
# 这时候一煎吧
Let's fry it now
# 煎完以后就翻过来
Then, flip it again
# 咱们就开始切一下
And we can cut it
# 以后多带点这些菜
You should bring more of these dishes
# 然后献给广大的网友们
And present them to our broad audience
# 牛肉煎粉条
Beef with fried vermicelli
# 二伯 来
Er Bai, please
# 大爷先来吧
Da Ye should taste it first
# 您来吧您来 我先拍您
After you. I'm shooting the video for you first
# 你看这粉条真筋道 大爷
See? The vermicelli is very chewy
# 你愿意吃哪块你吃哪块
Taste whichever you like
# 我吃粉条多那块
I'll have the one with more vermicelli
# 你说说
Tell us
# 怎么样
How is it?
# 这个菜我也是第一次看到
This is my first time to see this dish
# 这个菜
This dish...
# 我希望李党呢
I hope that Li Dang
# 把更多更好的接地气的美食
can bring more down-to-earth dishes
# 然后呈现给我们广大的网友们
and present to our broad audience
# 可以
Good
# 馋的我还咬了一口
I just bit myself
# 里边肉少啊 二伯咬舌头了
There's not enough meat. Er Bai is biting his tongue
# 今天二伯刚才给你提要求了
Er Bai just had a wish for you
# 师父也给你提要求
Your master, me, also have one demand for you
# 回来北京这几天
During your days back in Beijing
# 天冷了多穿点衣服
Be sure to keep warm since it's cold
# 回老家嘞
When you go back home
# 河南有啥好吃嘞
Make sure that you collect
# 多搜集点儿
more recipes of delicious food from your hometown in Henan
# 欢迎大爷 二伯
I would always welcome Da Ye and Er Bai
# 上河南 商丘
to Shangqiu, Henan
# 河南人民欢迎您
People in Henan welcome you!
# 大爷这个
Da Ye
# 河南话说的挺溜啊
can speak in Henan dialect very well
# 我到那还得学习学习
I need to learn more when I go there
# 你说一个北京人民欢迎他
Say 'People in Beijing welcome him'
# 欢迎你徒弟 你用河南话说一个
'Welcome your disciple', try to say that in Henan dialect
# 这我说不好
I cannot say it properly
# 北京人欢迎河南的 商丘滴
Beijing people welcome friends from Shangqiu, Henan!